什么是容器?
What are containers?
所以这可能比你们想象中的要简单得多。
So that's probably more simple
than some of you may think.
你们中的一些人可能已经知道了这个问题的答案。
Some of you might already know this,
the answer to this question.
但实际上没有这样的东西
But there's actually no such thing,
一个是 Linux 容器的东西，对吧 ?
one single thing that is
a Linux container, right?
我们想知道一个容器就是这个，我们说，好， Linux，
We like to have this idea that a container
is this, we say, all right, Linux,
集装箱就可以了对吧
containerify that and
it just works, right?
而且还没那么简单
And it's not quite that simple.
Linux 容器实际上是在
A Linux container really is
actually a combination of at
Linux 中至少有三个不同的内核功能。
least three different kernel
features within Linux.
这正是一个容器的理念。
That kind of culminate in this
idea of what a container is.
再说这都是命令行的
And again, this is gonna be
all here in the command line.
所以如果你有任何问题，请你去看看杰姆的课程。
So if you have any issues with it,
go ahead and check out Jem's course on it.
这是个不错的课程
It's a great course.
所以在我们开始进入一个容器之前
So, Before we kinda start getting
into what is a container,
我要给大家一点历史，说明为什么我们需要容器，对吗 ?
I'm going to give you a little bit the
history of why we need containers, right?
带领你完成我们今天所经历的旅程
Kind of lead you through the journey
of how we got to where we are today.
我希望你能想象一下
So I want you to picture for a moment that
你是一个大公司的工程团队的负责人对吧
you are head of a engineering
team at a big corporation, right?
您需要在某个地方托管您的 Web 站点。
And you need to host
your website somewhere.
我不知道你怎么变成了一个没有网站的工程师
I don't know how you became a head of
engineering with no website already.
但这就是我们为假设性而发现的情况，好吗 ?
But this is the situation that we find
ourselves in for this hypothetical, okay?
所以如果你 15 年前，或者 20 年前，做这个，你应该开始
So if you had been 15 years ago, or
20 years ago, doing this, you should start
想想，好吧，我要买一堆服务器。
thinking about, all right, well,
I need to buy a bunch of servers.
我得搞清楚我的数据中心要去哪了
And I need to figure out where
my data center's gonna go.
我要雇佣一堆人来管理诈骗
And I need to hire a bunch of people
that are gonna manage racking and
堆叠服务器之类的
stacking servers, stuff like that.
就像我在这里说的你和裸机服务器合作对吧
As I call it here,
you're working with the bare metal, right?
所以你要去戴尔公司你要去 EMC公司
So you're actually going to Dell,
you're going to EMC.
你会去一些真正大的云提供商。
You're going to some of these
really big cloud providers.
或者不是云提供商，而是硬件供应商和
Or not cloud providers,
but hardware providers and
说我需要多少服务器我需要这些东西
saying I need x amount of servers and
I need these kind of things.
然后，您必须担心物理安全性，数据中心。
And then you have to worry about
physical security, the data center.
你得担心温度的问题
You have to worry about the temperature.
你必须担心升级那些已经不够强大的东西。
You have to worry about upgrading things
that that are no longer powerful enough.
你得担心这类的事情
You have to worry about all
sorts of stuff like this.
对我来说，就是想坐在这里，整天写我的 JavaScripts 的开发者，
For me, the developer that just wants to
sit here and write my JavaScripts all day,
听起来很像我不想做的事对吧
that sounds like something I very
much do not wanna do, right?
这里有交易对吧
There are trade-offs here, right?
人们还是这样做的，对吧 ?
There are still reasons
that people do this, right?
目前仍有许多公司在裸机服务器上运行。
There are still lots of
company running on bare metal.
我想你们很多公司还在裸机服务器上运行，对吧 ?
I imagine many of your companies are still
running on bare metal servers, right?
更安全对吧
It's more secure, right?
因为你没和任何人分享对吧
Because you are not sharing
anything with anyone, right?
你控制一切
You control everything.
你控制着你的整个命运
You control your entire destiny.
如果你有这些规模经济的话，你可以便宜一些，
If you have these economies of scale,
it can be cheaper for you,
对，而不是在公云上做什么。
right, than doing something
in the public cloud.
如果你有任何非常敏感的东西
And if you have anything that's
extremely performance sensitive,
你可以调整你的盒子就像你需要的一样
you can tune your boxes to be as
whatever you need out of them.
但有很多问题，这很贵，对吧 ?
But it comes with a lot of problems,
this is expensive, right?
你要买的能力要比你能用得多，对吧 ?
You have to buy more capacity
than you can use, right?
如果你要打你的身份
Because if you're hitting your capacity,
这意味着你要把东西放在地板上
that means that you're
dropping stuff on the floor,
这意味着你总要有更多的能力
which means that you always have to
have more capacity than you're using.
我们的应用有很多季节性的季节性，对吧 ?
And a lot of has seasonality to our apps,
right?
所以如果你有足够的能力来处理 " 单身日 " 或 " 黑色星期五 " ，
So if you have enough capacity to handle
Singles Day or Black Friday, that means
你有一堆服务在今年剩下的时间里无所事事对吧
you have a bunch of service just sitting
idle the rest of the year, right?
你得担心破事对吧
You have to worry about stuff breaking,
right?
有时候 RAM 变坏了吧
Sometimes RAM just goes bad, right?
然后你得把它修好
And then you have to go in and fix that.
这也是你现在的问题
That's also still your problem now.
让我们说你需要更多的产能，对吧 ?
And let's say you need to
buy more capacity, right?
不像你可以说，嘿，库伯内特，给我另一个节点，对吧 ?
It's not like where you can just say, hey,
Kubernetes, give me another node, right?
而你只有一个
And you just have one.
你得再打电话给戴尔说，我需要更多的服务器，对吧 ?
You have to call up Dell again and
say hey, I need more servers, right?
我想写一个 Kubernetes 的供应商
I actually thought about writing
a Kubernetes provisioner that made
购买请求，对吗 ?
a purchase request, right?
然后当它回来并上线的时候
And then eventually when it comes back and
comes online,
那就把你的节点吐口水了吧
then it spins up your node, right?
这是最糟糕的想法
That's the worst idea.
这很贵，所以我还没写。
It would be terribly expensive and
that's why I have not written it.
我也没有足够的钱去做
I also don't have enough money to do that.
所以，嗯，只需要一个或两个月的时间，对吧 ?
So, Yeah, that only takes a month or
two, right?
这很简单
It's pretty much instant.
[ LAUGH] 希望你现在就知道了
[LAUGH] So
hopefully you're getting the point now.
裸机有它的存在对吧
Bare metal has its ups, right?
但它有很多淡化的问题。
But it has a lot of downsides.
这就是为什么很多公司不再做裸机服务的原因。
There's a reason why a lot of companies
don't do bare metal service anymore.
那么，让我们深入了解虚拟机。
So let's get down into
virtual machines then.
所以如果我有一个网络服务器
So if I have a Web server,
我是在数据场上的一个服务器上运行的，对吧 ?
I'm running it on one server
blade within my data farm, right?
我在裸机操作系统上运行一切
I'm running everything on bare
metal operating systems like that.
其实很酷的是我能拥有一个服务器的农场
Well, what would be really cool is I could
actually just have a farm of server and
那我就会有任意数量的服务器在运行，对吧 ?
then I could have an arbitrary amount
of servers running on them, right?
这就是虚拟机进入画面的地方，对吧 ?
And that's kind of where virtual
machines come into the picture, right?
所以我可以有一个服务器但是我可以有多个不同的操作系统
So I can have one server but I can have
multiple different operating systems
与虚拟机同时运行，对吧 ?
running at the same time
as virtual machines, right?
在这个意义上它们是虚拟服务器。
They're virtual servers, in that sense.
这将会非常有帮助，因为现在我可以扩大规模，
And that gets to be very helpful
because now I can scale up and
在我的数据中心容量范围内缩小，是吗 ?
scale down within my capacity
of my data center, right?
这很有帮助，因为我只需要管理能力。
And that that's helpful because then
I just have to manage capacity.
如果我有一个小队下线了
Cuz if I have one team go offline,
他们就会把他们的服务拿回来
they take down their service,
I can then reclaim that immediately and
再给它加些东西，就从这个其他的这个队网上来的，对吧 ?
add more stuff to it, right from this
other team that's coming online, right?
所以这种虚拟化策略允许我们分离 VM，对吗 ?
So this kind of virtualization strategy
allows us to separate VMs, right?
目前，我们还是要管理自己的硬件，还有
At this point, we're still having to
manage our own hardware and we still have
来管理我们的操作系统和司机还有其他的东西
to manage our operating systems, and
drivers, and all that kinda stuff.
但是，至少我们可以在自己的能力范围内扩大规模和规模。
But, at least, we can scale up and
kinda scale down within our own capacity.
所以，让我们来谈谈为我们解决的其他问题。
So, let's talk about something
else that this solves for us.
假设我们现在正在运行一个托管供应商，对吧 ?
Let's say that now we're running
a hosting provider, right?
某种类型的共享托管提供程序。
Some sort of shared hosting provider.
假设我有两个不同的客户
Let's say I had two different clients and
我刚把他们都从 root 用户的电脑中删除了
I just dropped them both with
root access to the same computer.
他们只是说，好了，现在运行你们的服务器。
And they're just say, all right,
now run your servers.
现在，如果你的皮肤开始爬行，那么好。
Now if you're skin is starting to crawl,
good.
这意味着你已经了解到这些了，对吗 ?
It means that you already
understand some of this, right?
但如果你的皮肤没有爬行，让我来为你爬行。
But if your skin's not crawling,
let me make it crawl for you.
所以，让我们想象你有两种类型的提供程序。
So let's imagine that you
have two sort of providers.
让我们说一个他们的名字是可口可乐，其中一个叫百事可乐，对吧 ?
Let's say one them's name is Coca-Cola and
one of them's name is Pepsi, right?
可口可乐决定在他们的服务器上存储，对吧 ?
And Coca-Cola decides to store on
their server recipe.txt, right?
现在，希望你能看到我在这里的情况。
Now, hopefully you can see
what I'm getting at here.
如果我们在同一台服务器上有百事可乐的话
If we have Pepsi on the same server,
they could just change directory over into
可口可乐的目录和秘方。
Coca-Cola's directory and
say secret recipe.
我知道了太棒了
I got it, great.
我不知道为什么在这种情况下我让百事可乐坏了
I don't know why I made Pepsi
the bad guy in this situation.
但他们肯定是坏人对吧
But they're definitely the bad guy, right?
好吧这就不太棒了对吧
[LAUGH] All right, so
this ends up being not great, right?
这就是为什么虚拟化也能有所帮助，因为现在它们处于不同的环境中
So that's why virtualization can also
help too because now they're in different
操作系统。
operating systems.
他们甚至都看不到对方对吧
They can't even see each other, right?
他们甚至不知道他们在同一台服务器上。
They don't even know that
they're on the same server.
对他们来说这些都是 Ubuntu 的副本
To them they just, all right,
here's a copy of Ubuntu.
你就在 Ubuntu 上就这样了对吧
You're just chilling out on Ubuntu and
that's it, right?
不过我们还是有问题的对吧
We still have problems here though, right?
如果我运行一个托管供应商和可口可乐
If I if I'm running a hosting provider and
Coca-Cola and
百事可乐在同一台电脑上的 VM 上
Pepsi are on VMs on the same computer,
well,
如果我是百事可乐我只能说在我的特定 VM内运行一个叉式炸弹
if I'm Pepsi I can just say run
a fork bomb within my particular VM.
这会消耗所有资源， CPU和内存，以及所有这些东西。
Which consumes all of the resources, and
CPU, and memory, and all that kinda stuff.
它会把服务器和
And it would take down the server and
它会把所有人都放在服务器上对吧
it would take down everyone on the server,
right?
这样，它们就会导致可口可乐的宕机，而这将是一个大问题。
So that way they could cause downtime for
Coca-Cola and that would be a big problem.
比掉下叉子炸弹的人要少得多
And much less nefarious than
someone dropping a fork bomb,
如果你还没有听到叉子炸弹的话我就把它丢在里面了
if you haven't heard of a fork
bomb I dropped a link in there.
这只是个简单的命令几乎能让整个系统
It's a little short command that just
takes down an entire system almost
马上
immediately.
很有趣的
It's kinda fun.
别在自己的电脑上运行
Don't run it on your own computer.
但你不能就这么简单的
[LAUGH] But yeah, much less nefariously,
you cannot just have
写了一个漏洞的人泄露了内存并把整个服务器都拿走了
someone that wrote a bug that leaked
memory and took down the entire server.
你想让他们自己冷静下来
And you want them to just
take themselves down.
你不想让他们把所有人都带走对吧
You don't want them to take
down everybody, right?
所以我们在这里仍然有一个问题
So that's kind of we still have
a problem here by just having
和越南船民一样
the same people on VMs.
现在，使用虚拟机，如您可能猜测的，您还可以限制多少。
Now, with VMs, as you may guess,
you can also limit how much.
好了，你只得到这么多的核，就能得到这么多的 RAM。
All right, you only get this many cores,
you only get this much RAM.
你可以缓解其中的一些解决方案。
And you can kind of mitigate
some of those solutions.
但我要给你们展示如何用 C 组的东西来做更多的事情。
But I'm gonna show you how to do that
even more with something called C groups.
所以我们在这里还有一点性能问题。
So we still have a bit of
a performance problem here, as well.
不是的，我说我十个服务器都在一个虚拟机内
It's not, let's say that I have ten
servers running as VMs all within one
在我的数据中心中被跟踪的服务器。
racked server in my data center.
但是我们这里还有一些开销让这个仍然是低效的
But we still have some overhead here
that's making this still an inefficient
系统，对吧 ?
system, right?
如果有台服务器在运行 10 个不同的服务器，那么我们就必须运行 10 个副本，
We have to run ten copies of, if we have
a server that's running ten different,
一个正在运行十个不同的 Web Service 的硅服务器，对吗 ?
a silicon server that's running
ten different Web services, right?
我们还得运行十个操作系统的副本。
We still have to run ten
copies of an operating system.
我们在 10 份操作系统上浪费了这些容量。
And we're wasting some of that capacity
on ten copies of the operating system.
如果我们能在操作系统上运行一个副本是很棒的，对吧 ?
It would be great if we could just run
one copy to the operating system, right?
这就是我在这里用容器暗示的东西。
So this is what I'm hinting
at with containers here.
所以，如果你想直接和越南船民一起玩，杰姆就会这样做。
So again, if you want to play with
VMs directly, Jem's course does that.
船民仍然是一个非常有效的选择。
And VMs are still very
much a very valid option.
我知道很多人还在使用 Azure VM 和 AWS ， EC2，对吧 ?
I know a lot of people out there are still
using Azure VMs and AWS, EC2, right?
非常，非常有效的事情还在用，
Very, very valid things still to be using,
and
仍然存在您要使用 VM的原因。
there's still reasons
that you want to use VMs.
所以你也应该和那些人一起玩
And so you should definitely
play around with those as well.
就像我说的杰姆在 Fronmaster Master 的课程是给你的
And like I said, Jem's course on
Frontend Master does that for you.
所以我觉得他和 DigitalOcean一起出去玩
So I think he goes out and
plays out with DigitalOcean.
好，这就给我们带来了公共云的情况，对吧 ?
Okay, so that brings us to the public
cloud kind of situation, right?
这会是微软 Azure 亚马逊网络服务公司
So this is gonna be Microsoft Azure,
Amazon Web Services,
Google Cloud Platform。
Google Cloud Platform.
你会经常听到我说 GCP 和 AWS 因为我在商界工作
Which you'll often hear me saying GCP and
AWS, because I work in the business and
我不禁要用缩略语。
I cannot help myself but use acronyms.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
他们已经把我带走了
[LAUGH] they've taken me.
这太好了因为我已经移动了数据中心
So this is great because now
I've moved the data center
离开我的特殊公司对吧
away from my particular company, right?
我不再需要这些管理员了
I no longer have to have these admins.
我不需要买实物
I don't have to buy physical space.
我不需要担心温度之类的事情
And I don't have to worry about
temperatures or anything like that.
我只是说嘿 Amazon Web Services 或 hey ， Microsoft Azure
I just say hey, Amazon Web Services,
or hey, Microsoft Azure,
给我另一个 VM 让我提供点东西
give me another VM and
let me provision something.
这些公司在世界各地拥有巨大的数据中心
And those companies have massive
data centers all over the world,
每一个都有 30 到 40 个不同区域。
each one of them has like 30 or
40 different regions.
这真的很棒。
So that's really great.
我们在这里得到规模经济的经济
We get the economies of scale here and
I just pay them for
我正在使用的 CPU 量的计量表，我使用的内存量。
the spinning the meter of how much
CPU I'm using, how much memory I'm using.
他们把所有服务都给我了
And they handle all those service for me.
他们负责更新硬件。
They handle updating the hardware.
你再也不用担心硬件了
You never have to worry about
hardware basically ever again.
如果你还在使用越南移居者
Now if you're still using VMs,
你还得担心作业系统，对吧 ?
you still have to worry about
the operating system, right?
他们把服务器给你
They give you the server.
但如果有很大的安全漏洞
But if there's a big
security vulnerability,
你得修补好吗
you have to patch it, right?
你得进去说 Ubuntu
You have to go in there and say Ubuntu,
升级到最新的 LTS 或类似的东西。
upgrade to the latest LTS or
something like that.
我觉得 LTS 是长期服务的
LTS stands for long term service, I think?
>> 支持。 >> 支持，感谢长期支持。
&gt;&gt; Support.
&gt;&gt; Support, thank you, long term support.
是啊这就是他们长期坚持的版本
Yeah, and that just means that's a version
that they maintain for a very long time.
所以，公共云，这很棒。
So public cloud, this is great.
你最后支付的钱可能比你要的要多
You end up paying perhaps a bit more
than you would have if you're running it
你自己
yourself.
但这里的交易是你不再需要雇佣员工了
But the trade-off here is you
no longer have to hire people.
而且人一般都很贵，对吧 ?
And people are usually very expensive,
right?
要管理物理数据中心，对吗 ?
To manage physical data centers, right?
所以这才是交易的一部分
So that's kinda the trade off.
通常，由于这个原因，在公共云上几乎总是一个好主意。
Usually, it's almost always a good idea to
be in the public cloud for that reason.
从人类的角度来看，这通常比较便宜。
It's usually cheaper from
the human perspective.
现在就得说一个前端的工程师可以自己管理
And it's getting to the point now that
a front end engineer can manage their own
服务器对吧
servers, right?
这在 15 年前是不可能的
Which would have never been
possible 15 years ago.
所以在这些类似的情境工具中，如 Terraform， Chef， Puppet， Salt，
So in these kinda situations tools
like Terraform, Chef, Puppet, Salt,
我们今天不谈论的事情
things that we won't be
talking about today.
我不认识他们你也不想学我
Cuz I don't know them and
you don't wanna learn them from me.
这些功能将非常有用，因为这允许您旋转服务器，提供这些服务器。
These will be useful because this allows
you to spin up servers, provision them.
当我说条款条款时，我的意思是安装正确的软件。
And when I say the term provision, what
I mean is install the correct software.
确保所有内容都是最新的，下载您的代码，
Make sure everything's up to date,
download your code,
开始运行代码所有这些东西
start running the code,
all that kinda stuff.
这就是这些工具对你非常有用的地方。
That's where these tools can
be super useful for you.
一定要检查他们是否有你想做的事
Definitely check them out if that's
something that you're interested in doing.
但我们仍在支付在云中运行整个操作系统的成本。
But we're still paying the cost of running
a whole operating system in the cloud.
我们还得管理操作系统。
And we still have to manage
the operating system.
如果我们能说我们的密码就好了
It would be nice if we could
just say here's our code.
这就是它需要的环境，执行这个，对吧 ?
Here's the environment it needs,
execute this, right?
这是一些种类的工件执行这一过程。
Here's this artifact of some variety,
execute this.
这就引出了容器的概念。
And that brings us to
the idea of containers.
容器给我们提供了所有这些安全特性
Containers give us all of
these security features and
所有这些虚拟机的资源管理功能。
all these resource management
features of virtual machines.
但它们重量轻得多是我最讨厌的术语
But they're much lighter weight,
which is a term that I hate but
我还是会在这里用的因为这是一个毫无意义的术语，对吗 ?
I'm still gonna use here because it's
a absolutely meaningless term, right?
什么是轻量级的，与什么相比 ?
What is lightweight and compared to what?
我觉得每个 JavaScript 框架都是轻质的，对吧 ?
I feel like every JavaScript framework
comes out is lightweight, right?
这才是最糟糕的
[LAUGH] It's the worst.
但我真的是认真的对吧
And but here I actually mean it, right?
你可以说
You can say for
请确保虚拟机的重量比运行裸机服务器的重量更轻。
sure that a virtual machine is lighter
weight than running bare metal servers.
而容器的重量比运行一个虚拟机更轻。
And the containers are lighter weight
than running a whole virtual machine.
所以基本上我在做的就是冻结一个文件系统。
So basically what I'm doing is
I'm just freezing a file system.
我把它变成了一个容器图像。
I'm dumping that into a container image.
然后我把它关掉，然后我就有了一些主机操作系统
And then I'm shifting that off, and then
I have some sort of host operating system
正在为我执行这些容器
that's executing these containers for me.
所以你还会有多个东西在一个宿主容器里运行
So you're still gonna have multiple
things running in one host container
系统，对吧 ?
system, right?
我们对可口可乐百事可乐的问题也有同样的担忧
And we kinda have this same worry about
the Coca-Cola Pepsi problem that I'm
就会在我旁边的
gonna be running this container and
then, next to me,
另一个容器就要开始运作了
another container's gonna be running.
我不知道是谁干的对吧
And I don't know whose it is or
what it's doing, right?
所以我也有同样的关注
So I have these same, similar concerns but
让我向您保证，由于容器的特点，无法相互了解。
let me assure you that with the features
of containers, they can't see each other.
他们不能和对方互动
They can't interact with each other.
他们甚至都不知道对方在那儿
They can't even know that
each other are there.
很多非常聪明的人一直在研究这个问题。
And a lot of very smart people have been
working on this for a very long time.
我很自信地说这很安全
And I feel pretty confident
in saying this is secure and
你肯定该走这条路了
you should definitely go down this path.
以前也不是那样的
It didn't always used to be that way.
现在是这样。
It is now that way.